[Music]
there was a guy on a motorcycle and he
had a t-shirt on and it said kick me in
the butt and I said do you know what
that says he says yeah it says I like
trees or something like that so I asked
penny what's it mean he gave me the
shirt it means how do you say it in tell
you uncle in caw-caw cause that effect
okay
share the cleanse with other people it
will work for you okay all right I want
to do the text okay because we're we're
getting behind so Nick it's both away
tuna okay the next kind of you pour toi
tumor engagement me Demba marijuana so
there was a Kadamba in Portola early
Tibetan Buddhist and somebody came to
him and said I don't believe there was a
Buddha it's like people who say there's
no landing on the moon it was all from a
TV studio or something then he said
they'd like a shaky table their day then
the gas a table the table came in
skillful means what kept out of the bus
okay
it means tricky he gave him a tricky
Dharma teaching he said owner catering
department did not come yang module I
know about your grandfather his
grandfather was famous his name was do
not go and he said so I'm sorry to hear
your grandfather didn't exist okay
young much day to day sharpen long JD he
agreed the same then the guy got
offended and he said don't say my father
my grandfather didn't exist he was
famous and we have this this letter
that he wrote famous letters that he
wrote ten photo I said okay Rick
Poquoson say lichte go through so we
should record that as a word okay rick
wob' gods who is a logic term it means
parallel reasoning parallel reasoning Oh
your grandfather must have existed
because the letters that the great
letters he wrote are still in your
family right yes well then the Buddha
existed too because we have great things
that he wrote okay Danny it's called
parallel logic ginger typical summer Sun
gauge a I'm JD Chuck Jane means a
footprint handprint okay we call the
footprint left behind by the Buddha is
syndrome these beautiful books you know
990 teachings by the Buddha still exist
in Tibetan direct teachings like diamond
cutter Sutra 990 and 3,700 others from
India okay and some great ones from
China huh
okay Sheen a curse on gay Jim Burnie
champa jinsol then the guy changed his
mind
okay I accept Buddha came to this world
but I think it's good to be honest and
say I didn't see a Buddha yet okay a
monk or nun one of the worst things a
monk and nun could do publishing the
four big bodies one of them is to lie
about your spiritual life or to make
imply to people you know they say are
you in our union like wow you know
I'm not supposed to say then you imply
that you are
okay so the biggest lie you can make in
Buddhism is about your spiritual no more
okay so we have to be careful not to
imply that we reached a level that we
haven't reached okay that's a big bad
karma okay
we could come anyways okay NEPA depend
on Chinese so we had negative we had
negative because thou refuse us negative
refuge for us I think we had three so
far yeah one for Buddha was for Dahmer
one for summer once you've taken refuge
in the Buddha yeah don't take Laura
refuges okay once you've taken refuge in
the Dharma don't hurt anybody
once you've taken refuge in the Sangha
yeah don't get real close to people who
who think this is not practical okay
okay now positive guidelines okay we've
had your beloved enemy posit and our
refuge Val number one
Dumbo's Sangha Celtic so many
me is called silver lekha in
sanskrit and it means the letter to a
friend written by Nagant you know
and by the way there's a couple of
letters to friends in the ten year but
this is the most famous by the way if
you want to teach a short laundry room
that's a great book to teach and
rinpoche myeloma translated it with my
enemy are an animal
just kidding not
he's smarter than me and his cadet is
much better than mine and his Sanskrit
is 10 times better than mine so I don't
like him okay
I'm just being honest but I got over it
because I moved away for 20 years okay
if you can't overcome a better habit
just leave the leave the place when you
go back it will come back okay
he thought that he who is the king man
can't keep our tindalia keep a champion
and keep a church so even a blurry image
made of wood
okay cheap one why people will still
respect it and we talked about it that
any Buddha image you see ultimately it
came from someone who saw the Buddha in
the past okay
so respect anybody means I'm not so
crazy about Buddha images from Thailand
they they all have this kind of you know
but I respect them okay so charlie
respect them okay Jason Betar sonniku
subdued also yep this gear which
normally means cause means material from
which something is made so about three
percent of the time you means the
substance use for the for the sculpture
okay so McNally so you member means
lousing we call the sculptor made a
super ugly Buddha okay sculptor was not
so skilled and yeah metal bottom saticon
on the chapter me and Chen Dafeng
introducing chakra satakam satakam means
dharma garbage death
in Tibet they would build small like our
pump house in the valley or those
outhouses they would build a small adobe
building and if you have an old painting
or you have a Buddha the broken arm
we're not allowed to throw them in the
garbage
so these are spiritual garbage shed and
you can throw old Dharma things in there
like old gushie Michael ACI course stuff
that you don't want anymore okay
somebody I knew was living in a tent
it's a geshe-la stop making courses I
don't have any place to sleep in my tent
okay Santa Kong monkey chug chug do
means broken pieces of Buddhist or talk
us okay
yang telah son gang milking your
joke when you see a statue or when you
see a painting you should treat it as if
it was the Buddha okay you should treat
it as if it was a high Lama okay even
that painting so there's all this
etiquette about paintings and you're not
supposed to pick them up by the head
you're supposed to roll them up
carefully by the way when you're rolling
up you're not allowed to touch the pink
part you roll it up this way from the
edges you're not allowed to roll it from
the middle you see there's all this
etiquette about not hurting the
paintings okay and it's interesting in
in in in Tibetan when we go to a temple
we say chin gel and which means you
don't say I'm going to look at the
paintings you say I'm going to meet the
Buddha you see so you think of the
images as a Buddha and you don't think
they're not normal
somebody saw Buddha in the Minish
somebody who painted this the painter of
the painter of the painter of the
painter in opinion
somebody saw Buddha so these are these
are very chemically powerful and you
have to treat them carefully okay so
don't get sloppy with your statues and
stuff
don't put peanut butter sandwich on top
of your Buddha hair in it now I've seen
some where's the hustle okay
people use it to hang their coat you
know don't do stuff like that okay
treat them as if they are atomic bombs
you know I will
I got a statue in my hospital and keep
it clean remember Jay had a feather
duster and he he would spend a couple
hours in the tempo I said what are you
doing in there and I said ginger I'm
meeting the Buddhist he liked to hang
out with the images more than me
I don't know why okay sorry no he do she
means think of them as a Buddha
themselves think of the statue or
painting as a brooder and treat them
that way okay run beggar girl emo dumb
song sir so people are defecating how
can we cook too sharp cook means the
inner sanctum sometimes even called gunk
on every gluto monastery major monastery
has a temple and inside the temple
there's a secret room called goon comb
and that's where they keep the tantric
deities and in centre may there's a
prayer that goes on there 24 hours it
never stops ever for I don't know 400
years or something nobody there's always
four or five months in there praying for
the monastery you know a day and night
there's what he calls shifts we take
shifts
so then in the grand Kong people tend to
put the most valuable statue by material
if it's gold they keep it in there if
it's bell metal they keep it in there
there's a beautiful statue of rembert a
full-size in the gunk on that ceremony
in the secret room at my monastery if
you ever go there behind the altar
there's a secret room and there's a
full-size clay Statue of Liberty there I
was there when they made it it was kind
of cool okay Frank they're soaking
cooler Deborah chip chip so we tend to
have more faith for the expensive
statutes than the cheap sketches and
that's assignment you don't understand a
statue okay
so every statue of the Buddha even the
ones they sell in the garden stores to
keep you know they buy them from
Thailand and people just use them to
plant the bulbs on them and stuff we
should still treat them with respect
okay okay Jim ballet campus inaudible
then if they find a statue made of clay
they think that's not so spiritual
because it's not as expensive that's a
wrong idea charlie doing solar doubling
Sheila suction shock made the machines
have to come to kill it in value then if
you have an image that you have to throw
out be careful not to thrown in the
garbage
don't make Dharma garbage with other
garbage so I don't know the schedule
I had the schedule for I had malicious
list of donations to make so that's
Dharma garbage after you make your
twenty thousand dollar donation
don't throw that paper away on the
ground or something like that like treat
it
Dharma people have two sets of garbage
like recycling bins and Dharma bin
okay then replicate would always burn
his diamond garbage he wouldn't you know
he would burn it once a month or
something like that so we're not
supposed to mix old old retreat
schedules with garbage or something like
that all right
that's called quick dad children to kill
D gnarly senator Keller here he makes a
joke somebody asked me did this llama
make jokes he did they're kind of
Tibetans are cooking you tell it to bed
joke to American they're like if you
throw Dharma into the garbage you are
throwing your good comma away also he
said that I say no more comment on some
Lamas of the past so done okay one more
sentence station deuk-gu tongue so young
Moomba non-consumptive de meillan gil
java so groggy coin German Tiger maple
people with old Trancas old paintings
they tend to take off the silk which is
valuables and they treat their painting
as not valuable they keep the still can
make something out of it make sure wait
opinion so don't try to cheat the both
with respected dopest Oh Clank equation
I take admitted sorry
Ruka thought yen this is a sign that the
roots of your karma inside of you are
rotting rotten okay you should treat the
whole thing with respect
okay all right
sorry take it I'm renting tonight by the
way so we're going to stop there for the
alarm room I'm sorry we took so long in
the food but I think it's important so
you could be healthy your mind gets more
clear if you do that fast you'll find
your mind is much clearer it took me
many attempts to be successful like I
gave up many times in the past so keep
trying
it always won't always be successful
right away there's debate at four
o'clock come ok it's cool we're going to
have fun and at 5:30
there's review groups we didn't prepare
any special review groups so what I
suggest is just go to the jetsam Campus
Center sit down with your friends make a
plan for me that we did this morning
okay
might make a plan or just take a rest
okay we get evaluations every retreat I
think you're doing them when you did
them already at one o'clock you were
supposed to do them anyway we actually
read them and we meet we have meetings
about them and a lot of people said the
schedule was too tight and it felt too
tight so we're going to give you a break
okay because you're also getting up
early hopefully so 5:30 to 6:45
meet with your friends discuss your
plans if you want if you just want to
goof off goof off okay go faster
all right then